Damilare Odunayo Samuel

sdamilare420@gmail.com 🔀

08163502922

07080491060 1, John Adebiyi Street, Off Igando Road, 💡

Ikotun, Lagos

https://www.linkedin.com/in/damilaresamuel26 in

CAREER OBJECTIVE

A freelance software developer who seeks to become a successful expert in the field of Information Technology by channeling technical knowledge and skills to ensure professional and personal growth. A dedicated and enthusiastic individual who seeks to work for an organization which provides the opportunity to improve skills and knowledge to grow along with the organization.

EDUCATION

MSc in Computer Science University of Lagos (In view)

BSc (Hons) in Computer Science Lagos State University 2011-2015

SSCE

Golden Touch College 2004 - 2010

EXPERIENCE

Web design Frontend Trainer (Contract)

Ekobits ICT Academy (17th Aug 2020 - 11 Sept 2020)

- Introduced concept of web design and development to trainees.
- Taught fundamentals of web in html and css to the trainees.
- Explained concepts such as image tag, forms, links, flex, external styling etc.
- Formulated manuals while giving helpful links to the trainees.
- Introduced GitHub for the storage of their projects.
- Guided the participants in developing and hosting their websites on github.

Python Backend Trainer (Contract)

Ekobits ICT Academy (June 2020 – July 2020)

- Taught basic python to the trainees and gave tasks to test their knowledge virtually.
- Taught and explained concepts in backend stacks such as flask and django to the trainees using a project based approach.
- Developed a todo-app model in flask and django, created rest APIs for the models to be consumed by front end stacks in react js and vue js.
- Monitored the trainees' performance to know students' performance.
- Took attendance of trainees.
- Guided the trainees' all through to their project defense and presentation.

Python/Data Science Trainee

Bincom ICT Solutions (Mar 2019 - Apr 2019)

- Received training on basics of Python and some fundamentals in data analysis. such as the use of libraries including NumPy and Pandas.
- Learnt how to create a simple hello world website using Django.
- Collaborated with team members to debug basic python issues.

Software Developer Trainee

Moat Academy for Developers (Jan 2019 - Mar 2019)

- Learned and designed front end graphics for websites.
- Developed team communication skills for weekly projects.
- Learned and performed software testing to uncover bugs and troubleshoot issues.
- Learned and developed ER diagrams for databases using MySQL Workbench tool.
- Learned about the Flask framework.
- Developed a web application project that help the masses especially university students within Lagos find hostels and houses using Flask and MySQL database.

PROJECTS

E-Commerce Site (Side Project)

- Built an e-commerce site that is capable of performing basic e-commerce activities such as listing various products, their prices and their categories.
- Users can view items, add items to cart, remove and update a particular item from the cart before checking out.
- The total cost of the cart is then calculated and displayed to the user for checkout and payment.

CRM App (Side Project)

- Designed a customer relationship management app for an e-commerce.
- Admin can view customers' details and orders, process customers' orders like update and delete orders.
- Admin can also remove a particular customer.
- Users can sign up and login via the built in django-authentication framework.
- Users can update their personal details as well as their orders.
- Users can search for products based on several metrics such as categories, date range, and tags.
- Users can view the available products, make orders and view the status of their orders.

Blog App (Side project)

- Designed a blog application that performs CRUD operations.
- Users can register and login, create, read, update, and delete posts, They can also share posts via mail and comment on posts.
- They can change/update their profile whenever e.g. change profile picture or personal details.
- Technologies used include: HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap4, SQLite, and django.

To-Do App (Side project)

- Designed a todo-application that allows the users to create tasks.
- Users can delete tasks also and update tasks.
- Each task becomes crossed as completed when done.
- Technologies used include: React and Django REST.

Website Developer

- Designed a school website for a school.
- Integrated a chat feature via facebook chat plugin.
- Integrated a payment option using paystack payment gateway.
- Technologies used include: HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap4, Django and Postgres DB.
- Link: http://www.newworldischolar.com/

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Programming Language: Python and JavaScript
- Frameworks and Web: Flask, Django, Django REST, Node js, Express js, React js, Bootstrap4, CSS3. HTML5.
- Version Control: Git and Github
- Databases: MySQL, Postgres DB, Mongo DB, and SQLite
- Cloud Services: Digital Ocean, Netlify, and Heroku

PERSONAL SKILLS

- Great team player.
- Apt listener.
- Practical oriented and result focused.
- Good time management skills.
- Leadership skills.

REFERENCES

• Available on request.